so let's go back to our question of why
we need consistency we have already seen
an example in our quiz that something
beyond coherence is needed for a
data-ready flag synchronization to work
another similar example is thread
termination where a thread creates
another thread now that created thread
let's call it b
does a lot of work and updates some data
while thread a goes and waits until b
exits and it really happens by doing a
system call in thread a and then the
system really will wait for b to mark
that it's done and then when thread b
really is done the operating system will
mark that b is done and here we have a
very similar situation inside the
operating system that we have here which
is the check for be exiting might be
branch predicted and then confirmed
while in fact thread b is not done when
we branch predict this so what we need
is some sort of additional set of
ordering restrictions that are going to
prevent the weird situations that we can
get into without any consideration for
consistency and again this goes beyond
coherence alone we already saw that
coherence doesn't really help us here